## **Max Calcroft**





maxcalcroft@gmail.com





maxcalcroft



GitHub.com/maxcalcroft

#### **Profile**

I am a mechanical engineering graduate with experience as a research engineer, being involved in all stages from data processing and analysis to report writing and identifying vehicle market trends for managers and external clients. I helped lead the development of the first of it's kind consumer focused project with the UK government for automated driving, working with multiple project partners internationally whilst simultaneously working on other research projects independently. The success of this international project led to extra government funding for my previous company. I am deeply interested in cryptocurrency and markets, having taught myself technical analysis, developing several quantitative trading strategies for Bitcoin derivative contracts as well as using blockchain explorers, on chain data tools and DeFi analytics for personal research.

### Skills/Experience

- Research and report writing covering market trends and protocol development for one of the EU's lead vehicle research centres
- Strong interpersonal skills, having liaised with senior managers to technicals throughout Europe for companies such as Continental, BMW, Mercedes
- Experience in fast paced research company often fulfilling multiple roles

- Personal experience with on-chain analysis tools (Glassnode, Etherscan etc.)
- Pinescript coding
   language (Trading View)
- Python (NumPy, Pandas)
- Spanish (Intermediate)
- French (Basic)

#### **Interests**

I have a keen interest in cryptocurrencies and decentralised finance and often study markets, trading cryptocurrencies using quantitative analysis strategies I have created based on indicators and historical data. I have also taught myself Pinescript to develop and code indicators and strategies for trading derivatives and like to keep up to date with web3/fintech innovations and macro-economic trends.

## **Work Experience**

#### THATCHAM RESEARCH (Vehicle Research Centre)

October 2021 - September 2022 (Fixed term contract)

**Position:** Research Engineer

- Conducted research on emerging assisted driving technologies, protocols and legislation, independently performing data analytics and producing research reports and presentations for managers and UK regulatory bodies to influence policy
- Attended public and industry events, subsequently forming partnerships for projects and influencing the general public on vehicle safety via demonstrations and discussions
- Helped lead development and write report and framework for first of its kind project between multiple countries and disciplines liaising with multiple teams
- Disseminating vehicle test data and technical information into concise readable reports for internal and external team members, identifying trends in the automated/autonomous vehicle sector for various technical topics
- Fulfilled multiple roles in research, cybersecurity, technician etc. adapting to new projects, often working on multiple concurrently across teams

# HULLEY & KIRKWOOD

(Building Services
Engineering Firm)
2017-18 / Plymouth, UK
Position: Full time
engineer

#### **OTHER**

Farm Hand - 2019-2020 / Victoria, Australia Hostel shuttle driver - 2019 / NSW, Australia Landscaper - 2020 / Surrey, UK Barista - 2020-2021 / Santa Teresa, Costa Rica

## **Education**

## **Plymouth University**

September 2015- May 2019

Devon UK

2:1 Bachelors degree in Mechanical Engineering

Dissertation - focused on building a small scale autonomous vehicle using Raspberry Pi and LiDAR

- Self taught Python and ROS in order to implement object detection on moving buggy, troubleshooting software and hardware issues and producing detailed analysis of LiDAR effectiveness under varied conditions when compared with ultrasonic sensor (Obtained a 1st)